Dr. Grant, I'm on 200 mg a week sip. My
libido is still off. Any suggestions?
Lower the dose, I guess.
I would start with that, but libido is
not primarily hormone driven at all.
I have seen so many guys who have low T
in my clinic before health train wrecks
even and their libido is through the
roof and vice versa guys who are healthy
as can be
libido has never been good for them
their whole life and then everything in
between.
Libido in my opinion like I know for my
own self my wife like and people we
talked to like your life circumstances
your stressors what you have on your
mind all those things are going to play
way more into libido. Your relationship
status like how good is your
relationship? Are there stressors with
that?
But just work life kids life being busy
things that we see in general especially
again in Western countries people are
blowing and going all the time and not
they're not we do not
put the effort our general health like
we should. We do not get relaxation when
we should we don't get out in the sun
like we should. A lot of people do just
not ticking the right boxes food choices
I think affect it as well.
So there's there's a litany of things
and variables and I think when people
try to hone in on just no it's got to be
the testosterone that that's the one
thing I need to tweak to get it up. It
may be you got to try it. The problem is
you get transient effects with libido
when you change your dose. A lot of guys
will do that they'll chase that dragon
forever. Oh when I ramped my dose my
libido got better for 2 weeks and then
it went back. Yeah, I know it's
transient. You can't keep it like that.
It's it's just cuz you perturb the body
and you pushed it out of homeostasis and
for some reason that drove libido up. I
don't know why
but we see that all the time. It just
but it doesn't it doesn't last. So to
get a lasting libido the other thing is
expectations. Are you expecting to have
what's your expectations for your libido
to be? Every day you want it all the
time you want it every day? I mean
that's not natural per se a lot of us as
we as we age and life does get busier
people just don't think about sex as
much
and a lot of times it gets better after
retirement when people again have more
free time like when we go on vacation
sex drive is better cuz we're relaxed
we're enjoying we turned off a lot of
the switches that are keeping us
distracted. So you have to think about
all that too is where where should your
libido be based on the life
circumstances you have at the time and I
just I I think people have got to start
being more self-reflective about that
for sure. I'm not knocking that the
hormones might affect it cuz I have seen
where libido's were great and then you
add in a hormone and all of a sudden
libido seems to tank. Again is that
proof of causation? No cuz other things
could have been going on at that same
time
but it's worth exploring. It's worth
going well let's see if we can tweak
your protocol a little bit. My libido
did improve when I switched from
injections to cream but guess what? I
changed other variables in my life at
the same time. And I'm not like a
walking horn dog. I mean it's just I was
more receptive when the time came. Just
cuz I felt better. I just felt more
mentally clear cream than injections. I
didn't have the brain fog. So that made
me more receptive from a libido
standpoint but it's not like I'm walking
around like like a teenager. You know
what I mean? Like where because that
that should change as we get older when
we understand the meaning of sex and the
meaning of relationships. I think that
libido should probably change over time
too but that's just that's a different
topic. Great advice Jordan great advice.